Finding Aid for the Louis Thurston Nicholas Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- PERSONAL AND BIOGRAPHICAL—SOUTHWESTERN AT MEMPHIS
  - with accompanying letter, (May 8, 1934) (Box 118, Folder 15) Southwestern at Memphis—Examination Books (French))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Certificate Hall of Fame, 1934 (Box 118, Folder 16))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper Clippings and programs from 1930’s when L.N. was a student (Box 119, Folder 1))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper Clippings and Programs, 1030’s and others (Box 119, Folder 2))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Publications—Alumni Magazine, October/Nov. 1931 The Journal, Dec. 1931, June 1932* *Ein Heldenleben by l.N. (pp.31-33) (Box 119, Folder 3))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Programs—Vesper Service April 15, 1945; Memorial for William N. Mallory, April 1, 1945; and other programs 1939--1975 (Box 119, Folder 4))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Alumni List (Nashville, 1958) (Box 119, Folder 5))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Photograph Class of 1934, Reunion May 31, 1959 (Box 119, Folder 6))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Southwestern News, 1959 (Box 119, Folder 7))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Catalogue of Paintings by Carroll Cloar, 1963 (Box 119, Folder 8))
  - Southwestern at Memphis/Rhodes—Program—Inauguration of John David Alexander, Jr. as 16th President, May 1966 (Box 119, Folder 9))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Program—Inauguration of James Harold Daughdrill, October 20, 1973 (Box 119, Folder 10))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Homecoming, 1979 (Box 119, Folder 11))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper—Southwestern Today, Jan. –Dec. 1975 (Box 119, Folder 12))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper—Southwestern Today, Jan. –Dec 1976 (Box 119, Folder 13))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper—Southwestern Today—, March, May, October 1977 (Box 119, Folder 14))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Newspaper—Southwestern Today—, June, Nov., Dec. 1979 (Box 119, Folder 15))
  - Southwestern at Memphis –Newspaper—Southwestern Today—, July, August 1981 (Box 119, Folder 16))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Bulletin—Annual Report and other publications (Box 119, Folder 17))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Annual Report 1971 and other news (Box 120, Folder 1))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—The Bulletin of Southwestern at Memphis, 1970-71; 1983 (Box 120, Folder 2))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—The Bulletin of Southwestern at Memphis, 1972-1974 (Box 120, Folder 3))
  - Rhodes College—Class Agent Handbook, 1986 –87, Louis Nicholas class of 1934 (Box 120, Folder 4))
  - Rhodes College—Annual Report, 1990 –91, 1991-92 (Box 120, Folder 5))
  - Rhodes College/Southwestern at Memphis—Alumni Member 1993- 1994 Red and Black Society; Program, January 1988 (Box 120, Folder 6))
  - Rhodes College—Honor Roll of Donors, 1994-95 (Box 120, Folder 7))
  - Rhodes College—Chamber Music Recital Homecoming, 1999 (Box 120, Folder 8))
  - Rhodes College Magazine, Winter 2002 (Box 120, Folder 9))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—“A Message to Men and Women of Vision” (Box 120, Folder 10))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Papers from Southwestern Music Club (Box 120, Folder 11))
  - Southwestern at Memphis—Southwestern Songs-Booklet (Box 120, Folder 12))
  - Rhodes College—Materials (Box 120, Folder 13))
  - Southwestern/ Rhodes College—Materials (Box 120, Folder 14))
  - Rhodes College Correspondence, Nov. 1991-December 1998 (Box 120, Folder 15))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Class Notes, Summer 1951 (1) (Box 121, Folder 1))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Class Notes, Summer 1951 (2) (Box 121, Folder 2))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Class Notes, Summer 1951 (3) (Box 121, Folder 3))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Personal Notes of L.N. 1952 (Box 121, Folder 4))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Bulletin- 1958, 1961 “Expression of Faith” (Box 121, Folder 5))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Progress, 1970-71 (Box 121, Folder 6))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Music and Arts in Education News, Spring 1984, Winter 1985, Fall 1987 (Box 121, Folder 7))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Newsletter TC Today, Fall 1984, Spring 1985 (Box 121, Folder 8))
  - Teachers College, Columbia University—Brochure—Alumni College in Tuscany October 12-19, 1999; Danube Passage; Burgundy (Box 121, Folder 9))
  - University of Michigan School of Music Programs, (1936 –37) (1937-1938), (1939-40) (Box 121, Folder 10))
  - University of Michigan—May Festival Concerts—Programs—May 12, 13, 22, 23, 25, 1939; Choral Union Concerts, 1939-40 (Box 121, Folder 11))
  - University of Michigan—Course Cards, 1938-39 (Box 121, Folder 12))
  - University of Michigan Musical Society—May Festival Program 1941 (48th Annual) (Box 121, Folder 13))
  - University of Michigan—Musical Society –May Festival Program 1958 (65th Annual) (Box 121, Folder 14))
  - University of Michigan School of Music—Alumni Newsletter 1945; other materials (Box 121, Folder 15))
  - University of Michigan—Alumni Fund—Third Annual Report, 1955-56, 1964 (Box 121, Folder 16))
  - University of Michigan—School of Music Newsletter, May 1963 (Box 121, Folder 17))
  - University of Michigan Founder’s Day Celebration Concert, Feb. 24, 1979, Program and related materials (Box 121, Folder 18))
  - University of Michigan, University Musical Society, 1981-82 (Box 121, Folder 19))
  - University of Michigan—Interlochen National Music Camp, (1985-1987) (Box 121, Folder 20))
  - University of Michigan—School of Music and other U. of Michigan events, (1981 – 1991) (Box 121, Folder 21))
  - Programs of Recitals by Louis and Sarah Nicholas, (1948-1974) (Box 122, Folder 1))
  - Letter by Ray Council with biographical information about L.N. and S.L.N (Box 122, Folder 2))
  - Sarah E. Lacey—Graduation Recital Program, University of Michigan, May 23, 1934 (Box 122, Folder 3))
  - Sarah Nicholas (Sally)—The Triangle Mu Phi Epsilon, Feb., 1942 (Box 122, Folder 4))
  - Sarah Lacey Nicholas—Accompanist in Messiah, April 18, 1943 (Box 122, Folder 5))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Accounts Notebook, 1946 (Box 122, Folder 6))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Programs by her students, May 23, 1953, June 1, 1957 (Box 122, Folder 7))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Piano Recitals by Students, 1951, 1956, 1967, 1970 (Box 122, Folder 8))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Nashville Piano Teachers’ Association 1962 – 1975—Handbooks and other materials (Box 122, Folder 9))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Sigma Alpha Iota, Professional Fraternity for Women in Music, 1963 – 1964 (Box 122, Folder 10))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Judge for the 1966 Miss Nashville Pageant, Program with Notes (Box 122, Folder 11))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Honorable Judge 1968 Gallatin Jaycee Pageant (Box 122, Folder 12))
  - Sarah Elizabeth Nicholas—Personalities of the South 1969, entry p. 326 (Box 122, Folder 13))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Tennessee Music Teachers Association 1971, Student Auditions Handbook, Music Theory Test (Box 122, Folder 14))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Tennessee Music Teachers Association Constitution and other (Box 122, Folder 15))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Tennessee Music Teachers Association, Meeting, 1986 (Box 122, Folder 16))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—National Guild of Piano Teachers, Nashville Chapter 1970 –1973; Middle Tennessee Music Teachers Association, 1974 –75 (Box 122, Folder 17))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Peabody’s Women’s Club (1973/74, 1974/75), Piano Study Club (1974/75) (Box 122, Folder 18))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—National Geographic Society, 1975 (Box 122, Folder 19))
  - Review of Recital by Sarah and Louis Nicholas (Oct. 1976) and Program with short biography (Box 122, Folder 20))
  - Program from Feb. 26, 1985 (Free Will Baptist Bible College) “Introducing the Nicholases”; “Louis Nicholas, Tenor” (Box 122, Folder 21))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Obituary, December 1990, News from Hope College (Box 122, Folder 22))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas, Biography, obituaries May 1990 (Box 122, Folder 23))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Programs—Nashville Piano Teachers Assoc., 1980-1988 (Box 122, Folder 24))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Free Will Baptist Bible College Catalogue, 1958-59 (Box 123, Folder 1))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Free Will Baptist Bible College Catalog 1967/68 (Box 123, Folder 2))
  - Sarah Lacey Nicholas Artist Series—1993-94, Free Will Baptist Bible College (Box 123, Folder 3))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Music from Malecki Music House sent to Minister of Music at Free Will Baptist Bible College (Box 123, Folder 4))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—History of Free Will Baptist Bible College (Box 123, Folder 5))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Music Statement by Music Faculty Free Will Baptist Bible College; “How to Begin a Music Ministry” (Box 123, Folder 6))
  - Sarah Lacey Nicholas—Valentine Program (Box 123, Folder 7))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Notebook (Box 123, Folder 8))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Music Notebook (Box 123, Folder 9))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Music Notebook (Box 123, Folder 10))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Notes from Teaching (Box 123, Folder 11))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebook (Box 123, Folder 12))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebook (Box 123, Folder 13))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Student Music Theory Notebooks (Box 123, Folder 14))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Hope College, Holland Michigan (Box 123, Folder 15))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Theory Class—University of Michigan 1939, Feb.-June, Class Register (Box 124, Folder 1))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Class Notebook—Peabody College, Fall 1944 (Box 124, Folder 2))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Music for Piano Students (Box 124, Folder 3))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 4))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 5))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 6))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 7))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 8))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Student Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 9))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Student Notebooks (Box 124, Folder 10))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Teaching Career, Notes, Music (Box 125, Folder 1))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Tribute to S.L.N. from Tom Malone President of Free Will Baptist Bible College, letter dated, March 18, 1994 (Box 125, Folder 2))
  - Sarah E. Lacey—Comparative Analysis of Leonore Overtures II and III—Beethoven (Box 125, Folder 3))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas--Certificate—American College of Musicians (Box 125, Folder 4))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Certificates; Classroom Discipline by Emery Stoops; National Keyboard Ars Associates (Box 125, Folder 5))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Application for the Tennessee Governor’s School for the Arts (Box 125, Folder 6))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Pay receipts and other miscellaneous papers (Box 125, Folder 7))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Steinway Piano Promotional Materials (Box 125, Folder 8))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—“My Favorite Composer is Opus” (Box 125, Folder 9))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Christian Home Messenger Calendar, 1968 (Box 125, Folder 10))
  - Sarah L. Nicholas—Hammond Organ Clinic; Boston Music Co. Staff Chart (Box 125, Folder 11))
  - Joel E. Nicholas—Programs of Recitals by Joel Nicholas (Box 125, Folder 12))
  - Joel E. Nicholas (Jody)—American Motorcycle Schools, Inc. 1979-80 (pp.5, 19); Newspaper clipping “Jody Nicholas wins Race in Canada” (Box 125, Folder 13))
  - Joel E. Nicholas—“Motorcycle Maestro” article on Jody Nicholas in June 1961 American Motorcycling (Box 125, Folder 14))
  - Joel E. Nicholas—Birth Announcement Aug. 28, 1943 ;Commencement Program—Peabody Demonstration School, June 1, 1961; Grade reports 1957-59, Peabody Dem School (Box 125, Folder 15))
  - Joel E. Nicholas—Peabody Demonstration School Handbook 1958-1959 (Joel Nicholas 11th grade); Purse Prayer for Little People; Sewanee Mid-Winter Dances (Box 125, Folder 16))
  - Joel, David, Kevin Nicholas—Newspaper Clippings (Box 125, Folder 17))
  - David Nicholas in “Dapplegrim” Peabody Demonstration School, March 8, ?; Montgomery Bell Commencement Program, June 1, 1963 (Box 125, Folder 18))
  - Kevin Nicholas—School Reports and Photographs, 1961-63, 1967 (Box 125, Folder 19))
  - Kevin Nicholas—Honorable Judge 1968—Gallatin Jaycee Pageant (Box 125, Folder 20))
  - Photograph of Sarah Nicholas and son (date unknown) (Box 125, Folder 21))
  - Program of the Service of Grateful Memory of Louis T. Nicholas and the Eulogy by Minister Thomas Kleinert at Vine Street Christian Church, Nashville, TN January 7, 2006 (including biographical note); Obituary from The Tennessean, Dec. 29, 2005 (Box 125, Folder 22))
- ACADEMIC AND MUSICAL CAREER
  - Peabody College School of Music—Dissertation Proposals—Training for Development of Balanced Vocal Resonance and Vocal Sound Pressure (Box 126, Folder 1))
  - Peabody College School of Music—Dissertation Proposals—The Changing Role of the Band in American Colleges and Universities—1900—Present by Jerry Thomas Haynie (Box 126, Folder 2))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals (Box 126, Folder 3))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals (Box 126, Folder 4))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals (Box 126, Folder 5))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals (Box 126, Folder 6))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation of James Durroh—A Study of Plainsong in the Organ Compositions of Eight 20th Century French Composers (Box 126, Folder 7))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: Irving W. Wolfe: His Life and Contributions to Music Education by Donald R. Goss; Selected Sacred Solo Music of Francois Couperin; the Alto Flute: Its History and Musical Literature by Charles W. Smith (Box 126, Folder 8))
  - Peabody College—Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: The Operas of Francois-Joseph Fetis by Donald Hornbeck Boyer; Problems in vocal Pedagogy by John C. Burgin; Leo Sowerby: A Biography and Descriptive Listing of Anthems by B. Wayne Hinds (Box 126, Folder 9))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: Twelve Tone History by Charles Smith; A Study of Secular Italian Pieces by Michael Hernon; A Survey of Christian Hymnody in Iran by James Laster; Royal Prussian Wind-Band Music 1740—1797 by Eugene Waldo Steinquest; Royal Wind-Band Music of 18c. Prussia by Eugene Waldo Steinquest (Box 127, Folder 1))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: An Investigation of the Relationship Between the Musical Achievement of 6th Grade Students and Teachers in Kansas by David Edison Circle; Modern Chinese Songs: An Analytical Study of Selected Chinese Songs by Schuman C. Yang; A Critical Edition of the Dijon Chansonnier... by Charles E. Barret, Jr. (Box 127, Folder 2))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: The Concept of Rhythm in Music Analysis… by Willis H. Hackman (Box 127, Folder 3))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: Selected Choral Works of Francesco Foggia and Pompeo Canniciari… by Fred Ellis Ford; Vocal Problems in the Performance of Pierrot Lunaire by A. Schonberg by Sharon Mabry (Box 127, Folder 4))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: Anton Webern’s Three Poems for Voice and Piano... by James D. Hanson; An Exploration of Dorothy Sayers Theory of Creative Process as It Applies to Humanities Education Lovelle Atkisson (Box 127, Folder 5))
  - Dissertation Proposals and Outlines: Musica da Camera in Rome 1667—1700 by David Merrell Bridges (Box 127, Folder 6))
  - Monograph Submitted for Doctor of Musical Arts—George Peabody College for Teachers—James D. Hanson “Notes Inegales and Ornamentation in Francois Couperin’s Motets for Solo Voice” (1) Chapters 1-III (Box 127, Folder 7))
  - Monograph submitted for Doctor of Musical Arts—George Peabody College for Teachers—James D. Hanson “ Notes Inegales and Ornamentation in Francois Couperin’s Motets for Solo Voice (2) Chapters IV (Box 127, Folder 8))
  - Monograph submitted for Doctor of Musical Arts—George Peabody College for Teachers—James D. Hanson “Notes Inegales and Ornamentation in Francois Couperin’s Motets for Solo Voice (3) Chapter V, Appendix, and Bibliography (Box 127, Folder 9))
  - Monograph submitted for Doctor of Musical Arts—George Peabody College for Teachers—James D. Hanson “ A Performance Analysis of Anton Webern’s Drei Lieder, opus 25” (4) (Box 127, Folder 10))
  - George Peabody College for Teachers—Information to Faculty on Doctorate Work, 1967-1969 (Box 127, Folder 11))
  - Students—Resume of Jocelyn Kasper asking for letters of Recommendation from L.N. (Box 127, Folder 12))
  - Notebook—Repertoire, Fall 1965—c. Jan. 1975 (Box 128, Folder 1))
  - Notebooks with teaching notes (Box 128, Folder 2))
  - Teaching notebook (Box 128, Folder 3))
  - Notes (Box 128, Folder 4))
  - Notebook (Box 128, Folder 5))
  - A Handbook of French Phonetics (Box 128, Folder 6))
  - Student Notebooks—Leslie Bearden and other (Box 128, Folder 7))
  - Student Notebook (Arlene ?; Susan Lachmann) (Box 128, Folder 8))
  - Student Notebooks—Michelle Walker (Box 128, Folder 9))
  - Musicianship for Elementary Teachers—340A, Fall 1964 (Box 128, Folder 10))
  - Traditional Musical Elements in Webern’s Opus 25 by James D. Hanson (Box 128, Folder 11))
  - Lectures, Papers—“Salute to Don Cassel”; “Our Early Music”; “The Songs of Brahms”; “An Evening of Opera”; “ The Conductor as a Vocal Coach” (Box 129, Folder 1))
  - Lectures, Papers—“Some Reflections on Singers’ Diction’; Songs You May Not Know”; “Music at Christmas”; “Breathing for Singing”; “A Tribute to the Memory of John W. Work”; “Unlikely Corners in American Song”; “Changing Fashions in Concert Giving” (Box 129, Folder 2))
  - Lectures, Papers—“Response to Donald Read’s “The Academy in the 90’s” Review of Le Nozze di Figaro; NSO Preview Luncheon Talk: Rossini’s Barber of Seville (Box 129, Folder 3))
  - Lectures, Papers—“Trial by Jury” “Don Pasquale”; “Samson et Dalila”; “Le Nozze di Figaro”; “French Art Song”; “A Welcome” (NATS) (Box 129, Folder 4))
  - Lectures, Papers—WPLN’s Cumberland Chronicles 3/10/80; “Vowel Modification”; “Bicentennial Song”; Voice in Contemporary Music; “Puccini’s La Boheme”; “Wagner’s Use of the Voice” (Box 129, Folder 5))
  - Lectures, Papers—“Reasons for the Decline in Recital Attendance”; “Opera in Germany” NATS Keynote Address (Box 129, Folder 6))
  - Student Papers by Henry Arnold and John Carter—“A Study of the Requiems of Mozart, Verdi, and Brahms”; “The Requiem Masses of Mozart, Brahms, Verdi, and Faure” (Box 129, Folder 7))
  - Student Papers by Ellis Neece Elsey—“ Stabat Mater of Pergolesi, Rossini and Dvorak” (Box 129, Folder 8))
  - Student Papers by Rommie Bryan, Jr.—“Digest of The Art of Singing by W. J. Henderson; The Creation by Haydn by Dorothy Jones (Box 129, Folder 9))
  - Student Papers by Earl Hinton and Mary Louise Clements—Requiems of Mozart, Verdi, Faure, and Brahms; Saint Paul by Felix Mendelssohn (Box 129, Folder 10))
  - Student Papers by William C. Hoffman—Masses by Bach, Beethoven, Haydn (Box 129, Folder 11))
  - Student Paper by Jack Houts—Art Songs in the Different Countries by Composers; Art Song Literature by Maxie Cleera (Box 129, Folder 12))
  - “Reference Catalogue to Brahms 204 Songs for the Solo Voice” (Box 129, Folder 13) Student Paper of Tom Johnson (1978))
  - Student Papers by Marjorie A. Kerr and Genter L. Stephens—“The Passions According to St. Matthew and St. John”; “A History and Analysis of Mendelssohn’s Elijah” (Box 129, Folder 14))
  - Student Paper by Marvin Spry “A Study of the Seven Last Words of Christ” Composed by Haydn, Mercadante, and Dubois (Box 129, Folder 15))
  - Student Papers by Kernie N. Wessinger and by Shirley Bridges—An Examination of the Oratorio Dream of Gerontius by Edward Elgar (Box 129, Folder 16))
  - Student Papers—D. W. White—Judas Maccabeus; Irene Hardy—The Christmas Oratorio; William H. Yates—Handel’s Israel in Egypt (Box 129, Folder 17))
  - Scholarships, Auditions, etc. (Box 129, Folder 18))
  - Scholarships, Auditions, etc. (Box 129, Folder 19))
  - Scholarships, Auditions, etc. (Box 129, Folder 20))
  - Preparatory Paper in Art Song Literature by Fowler Stanton with lists of Songs on back (Box 130, Folder 1))
  - Miscellaneous Papers, Feb. 22, 1954—1969 (Box 130, Folder 2))
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1970—April 29, 1979 (Box 130, Folder 3))
  - Teaching Schedule, 1950-1955 (Box 130, Folder 4))
  - Bibliography of Research Studies in the Field of Music, June 1, 1960; “The Pedagogic Principles of Abby Whiteside” and other materials (Box 130, Folder 5))
  - Grade Analysis, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 6))
  - History of Musical Theatre—215—Questionnaire and Listening List (Box 130, Folder 7))
  - Vanderbilt University Spring 1979—History of Musical Theater Music -215 (Box 130, Folder 8))
  - Music 564 A—Paper by Jerry O. Williams “Wind Chamber Music in the Baroque Era”, August 1963 (Box 130, Folder 9))
  - Opera Lit. Exam (Don Runyon 12/21/72) (Box 130, Folder 10))
  - Seminar in Piano Playing, 1969-1978 (Box 130, Folder 11))
  - Repertoire for Art Song Literature—555A (Box 130, Folder 12))
  - Paper by Betsy Farlow: “Examples for Comprehensive Musicianship: A Practical Reality?”, April 1980 (Box 130, Folder 13))
  - H. Wiley Hitchcock—“Minimal Music and Minimal Art: Origins and Aesthetics” (9-2-88) (Box 130, Folder 14))
  - Students and their Repertoire (Box 130, Folder 15))
  - Students and their Reperoire—Music and Programs (Box 130, Folder 16))
  - Students and their Repertoire (Box 130, Folder 17))
  - Vocal Repertoire of Hortense Forman (Box 130, Folder 18))
  - Peabody College, School of Music—Theater (Box 130, Folder 19))
  - Peabody College, Music Theory Papers of Students (Box 130, Folder 20))
  - Peabody College, Directory, 1971-1972 (Box 130, Folder 21))
  - Peabody College, Repertoire for Art Song Literature, 555A, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 22))
  - Peabody College, Class Roll, Fall 1977 (Box 130, Folder 23))
  - Exams; Notes (Box 130, Folder 24))
  - “Some Recent Songs in English I am Willing to Recommend” (Box 131, Folder 1))
  - Seminar in Piano Teaching, 1969—1978 (Box 131, Folder 2))
  - Directory for Piano Workshop, 1974, 1975 (Box 131, Folder 3))
  - Peabody College—Music School Programs (Box 131, Folder 4))
  - Old French Pronunciation; Singer’s Repertoire; Gluck’s Treasure Chest—Il Telemoco and other (Box 131, Folder 5))
  - Peabody College, School of Music—German Diction (Box 131, Folder 6))
  - Peabody College, School of Music—“The German Sounds” (Box 131, Folder 7))
  - “Teaching Stress and Accents in Italian Words” (Box 131, Folder 8))
  - Italian Diction, Belmont College Fall 1980; Voice Lessons-Home- (Box 131, Folder 9))
  - Peabody College, Teaching of Singing—Phonetics; Vocal Pedagogy (Box 131, Folder 10))
  - Articles on Teaching Music: “The Child’s Voice” by D. West Richards; “A Brief History of the Development of the Art Song” by John Murray Kendrick (Box 131, Folder 11))
  - Workshops—Care of the Professional Voice and others—Vocal Institute—Vocal Arts (Box 131, Folder 12))
  - Care of the Professional Voice—Symposium at the Juilliard School of Music, 1986—1989 (Box 131, Folder 13))
  - “A Philosophical and Practical Approach to Teaching Composition in the Piano Studio” by Elizabeth Cormier (Box 131, Folder 14))
  - Music Writing Book (Box 131, Folder 15))
  - Teaching Notes—Types of Songs—Songs by Beethoven, Brahms, Schumann, and others (Box 131, Folder 16))
  - Teaching Notes—Franz Schubert, Gustav Mahler, Richard Strauss, Hector Berlioz, Gabriel Faure; Cesar Franck; Debussy, Ravel, Poulenc and others (Box 131, Folder 17))
  - Notes for Teaching (Box 131, Folder 18))
  - Notes for Teaching (Box 131, Folder 19))
  - Notes for Teaching—Vocal exercises (Box 131, Folder 20))
  - Notes on Teaching Singing (Box 131, Folder 21))
  - Notes for Teaching (including Belshazzar’s Feast) (Box 131, Folder 22))
  - Notes for Teaching—Medieval Dramatic Music; Opera as an Art Form; Opera Masters of the Early 18th Century (Box 131, Folder 23))
  - Opera Literature Teaching Materials; Listening List; Reviews and Outline (Box 131, Folder 24))
  - Opera Literature Teaching Materials (Box 131, Folder 25))